## CHRISTOPHER J. BURESCH

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Experienced software engineer with a focus on storage, distributed platform and infrastructure systems. Excited to design and implement scalable solutions for handling large amounts of data with commitment to delivering high-performing and reliable services. Ideally my next role would have leadership opportunities in the IC route.

### **SKILLS**

Proficient Languages: Scala, Java, Python, C#

Relevant Experience: Scalding / Hadoop MapReduce, HDFS, Airflow, Docker, K8s, Azure/GCP/AWS,

gRPC/thrift/protobuf, Bazel, Puppet, Terraform

Learning Languages: Rust, Go

#### EXPERIENCE

## Twitter, Inc. - Senior Software Engineer

Blobstore (Distributed Object Storage),

Dec 2018 - Nov 2022 Seattle, WA

As a team of 8 we stored 70PB of Twitter's public and private data in an on-prem multi-tenant multi-datacenter distributed key-value system. During my time on the team I owned the hardware health, all service automation, monitoring, tooling and deployments as well as custodial services and processes along with feature work.

## Selected Accomplishments

- Developed a chargeback model and automation to give customers daily resource cost across network and api usage, storage class, data locality and replication factor. This was an approvement over the previous manual process which only accounted for storage on disk on a quarterly interval.
- Developed a topology-aware locking service to ensure operational actors could operate independently safely without affecting service health. This presented opportunities like no-touch deployments and hardware lifecycle automation that removed weeks of developer operation toil, reduced pages by a magnitude, and increased deployments from monthly to weekly for our stateful backend.
- Developed compliance automation for kernel and firmware updates using Airflow as an orchestration engine. Rolls 8k machines across multiple datacenters in less than 30 days with no manual intervention and negligible service impact. As a result Blobstore was consistently in the top 5 of patched fleets across the company.
- Developed anti-entropy services and tooling to process large metadata dumps (billions of keys) to multi-instance workers to ensure data integrity.
- Migrated multiple services from baremetal to Aurora Mesos compute clusters to ease operational burden, improve developer velocity and service reliability as well as cut 6-figures from annual COGS.
- Maintained service monitoring and tooling, system health, system config, loadtesting, capacity planning and oncall.

# Microsoft Corporation - Software Engineer

Dynamics

Aug 2015 - Nov 2018 Seattle, WA

Worked remote to a small Switzerland-based follow-the-sun cloud infrastructure team tasked with managing the operational health of a Microsoft Social Engagement product's backend and various Elasticsearch clusters. Later switched to a backend product team developing an account management api for Dynamics CRM.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Gonzaga University

2011 - 2015 Spokane, WA

#### Clubs and Activities

Men's Rowing, Div. 1 2011-12 Computer Science Club 2012-15 Cycling Club 2013-15 ACM ICPC, PNW 2012, '13, '14 Math Club 2013-15 WSU Hackathon 2015

#### Achievements

3rd On-Site, ACM ICPC (PNW) 2013, 2014

#### **LEADERSHIP**

- Mentored new grads and interns with weekly 1:1's and adhoc sessions to help them ramp up into Twitter Engineering!
- Ambassador for Twitter Seattle 2021-2022. Responsible for planning events, creating opportunities for colleagues to socialize, assisting onsite operations management.

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Avid Mountain Climber! Summitted Mt. Baker, Mt. Shuksan, and Mt. Hood.
- 3d Printing enthusiast! I solve my everyday problems with plastic.
- I play tabletop, RPG and video games!